{"Topic": "Chemicals", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Which of the following acids is contained in the sting of bees and wasps", "op1": "formic acid", "op2": "acetic acid", "op3": "oxalic acid", "op4": "hydrochloric acid", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The enzyme that converts glucose to ethyl alcohol is -", "op1": "Invertase", "op2": "Maltase", "op3": "Zymase", "op4": "Diastase", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "A \u2018breath test\u2019 used by traffic police to check drunken driving uses ----", "op1": "Potassium dichromatic-sulphuric acid", "op2": "potassium permanganate-sulphuric acid", "op3": "Turmeric on filter paper", "op4": "Silica gel coated with silver nitrate", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the chief constituent of vinegar?", "op1": "oxalic acid", "op2": "formic acid", "op3": "citric acid", "op4": "acetic acid", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following acids is used in a car battery?", "op1": "hydrochloric acid", "op2": "sulphuric acid", "op3": "nitric acid", "op4": "carbonic acid", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Leakage of which of the following gases caused the Bhopal gas tragedy?", "op1": "Carbon monoxide", "op2": "Methyl isocyanate", "op3": "Hydrogen sulphide", "op4": "Nitrous oxide", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Formalin is generally used as an", "op1": "antiseptic", "op2": "anaesthetic", "op3": "stimulant", "op4": "preservative", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following chemicals is added to LPG to give out a strong smell?", "op1": "Ethyl mercaptan", "op2": "Dichloro diflouro methane", "op3": "Hydrogen sulphide", "op4": "Ammonia", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The sour taste of curd is due to the presence of which of the following constituents?", "op1": "acetic acid", "op2": "lactic acid", "op3": "formic acid", "op4": "citric acid", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following chemicals used in photography is also known as hypo?", "op1": "silver bromide", "op2": "silver iodide", "op3": "sodium thiosulphate", "op4": "silver nitrate", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Phenyl, commonly used in toilets is closely related to -", "op1": "Benzene", "op2": "Sulphuric Acid", "op3": "Sodium Thiosulphate", "op4": "Tetrachloroethylene", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The natural dye present in turmeric is known as", "op1": "Curcumin", "op2": "Cinnamin", "op3": "Phenolphthalein", "op4": "Methyl Orange", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which one of the following elements is used in the manufacture of fertilizers?", "op1": "Flourine", "op2": "Lead", "op3": "Potassium", "op4": "Aluminium", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which one of the following is used to induce artificial rain?", "op1": "Ammonium chloride", "op2": "Calcium carbonate", "op3": "Silver lodide", "op4": "Potassium Nitrate", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Nail polish remover contains", "op1": "benzene", "op2": "acetone", "op3": "petroleum", "op4": "acetic acid", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "By what name is Acetylsalicylic Acid better known?", "op1": "Vinegar", "op2": "Brine", "op3": "Saltpeter", "op4": "Aspirin", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "What is the role of catalyst in a chemical reaction?", "op1": "It increases the rate of reaction", "op2": "It decreases the rate of reaction", "op3": "It increases the yield of products", "op4": "It provides better purity of products", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What is the mixture of potassium nitrate, powdered charcoal and sulphur called?", "op1": "glass", "op2": "cement", "op3": "paint", "op4": "gun powder", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "When iron is left exposed in open air, it gets rusted. Which constituents(s) of air is/are responsible for rusting iron?", "op1": "1 and 2 only", "op2": "1 only", "op3": "2 and 3 only", "op4": "2 only", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "ect the correct answer using the code given below", "op1": "Bleaching powder", "op2": "Alum", "op3": "Borax powder", "op4": "Soda powder", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which one of the following is extensively used for sterilizing water?", "op1": "Potassium nitrate", "op2": "Calcium oxide", "op3": "Glucose", "op4": "Sodium chloride"}, {"Question": "Heavy Water implies", "op1": "Carbonated water", "op2": "Sea water", "op3": "Mineral water", "op4": "Deutrated water", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "When water itself combines chemically with some element of mineral it is called", "op1": "Carbonation", "op2": "Desilication", "op3": "Hydration", "op4": "Oxidation", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "KMnO4 can be used as a/an", "op1": "Disinfectant", "op2": "Insecticide", "op3": "Fertilizer", "op4": "Pesticide", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which chemical was an important symbol in India's struggle for freedom?", "op1": "Acetic acid", "op2": "Ammonium Nitrate", "op3": "Silver Iodide", "op4": "Sodium Chloride", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Dead organs are generally stored in formalin. Formalin is -", "op1": "aqueous ferrous sulphate", "op2": "aqueous formic acid", "op3": "aqueous ferric alum", "op4": "aqueous formaldehyde", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Contact lenses are made from", "op1": "polyvinyl chloride", "op2": "Lucite", "op3": "polystyrene", "op4": "Teflon", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which one of the following chemicals is used in beauty parlours for hair-setting?", "op1": "Phosphorous based", "op2": "Silicon based", "op3": "Iron based", "op4": "Sulphur based", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Alum is used as", "op1": "an analgesic", "op2": "a water purifier", "op3": "a fertilizer", "op4": "a disinfectant", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The rancid smell of spoilt dairy products is due to the liberation of", "op1": "acetic acid", "op2": "sulphuric acid", "op3": "butyric acid", "op4": "stearic acid", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following was known as Aqua Fortis in ancient times?", "op1": "nitric acid", "op2": "sulphuric acid", "op3": "butyric acid", "op4": "hydrochloric acid"}, {"Question": "Cyclotrimethylenetrinitramine is popularly known as -", "op1": "TNT", "op2": "RDX", "op3": "HTD", "op4": "TATP", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which was the first organic compound to be synthesised from inorganic ingredients?", "op1": "Urea", "op2": "Acetic Acid", "op3": "Sucrose", "op4": "Methane", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following has been found to contain anandamide, a neurotransmitter molecule (also known as molecule of extreme pleasure)?", "op1": "alcohol", "op2": "tobacco", "op3": "coffee", "op4": "chocolate", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Cyanide poisoning causes death in seconds because", "op1": "It causes lysis of red blood cells", "op2": "It breaks the electron transport chain", "op3": "It denatures enzymes of the heart muscle", "op4": "It causes cardiac arrest", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Photochemical Smog is a resultant of the reaction among", "op1": "High concentration of NO2, O3 and CO in the evening", "op2": "CO, O2 and peroxyacetyl nitrate in the presence of sunlight", "op3": "NO2, O3 and peroxyacetyl nitrate in the presence of sunlight", "op4": "CO, CO2 and NO2 at low temperature", "Answer": 3}]}